# JOSHUA SIMPSON

#### Young Systems Administrator with 20+ Years of Professional Experience

Bremerton, WA joshua.simpson@gmail.com 3608653273

(Sr) Systems Engineer with years of professional experience maintaining casino systems in a secure environment. With a high up-time requirement, I managed 20+ independent systems to provide less than a day of downtime in a year. Willing to relocate to: Bellingham, WA - Redmond, WA - Vancouver, WA

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Architect Network & Systems II**

Everi, Inc - Bremerton, WA

November 2001 to November 2019

Responsible for all of the systems, networks, and databases in Washington State for Everi (Previously Multimedia Games).

- Hired at 20 with MCSE certification as Field Technician
- Acquired Washington State Gambling Vendor Rep. License
- Worked from home office and responsible for communicating weekly duties with management, scheduling projects with all Everi and Casino staff, maintaining travel expense reports, and keeping a company vehicle well maintained.
- Supported Washington State Gambling Commission on securing, testing, validating, documenting, and approving proprietary solutions for Class 3 slot machines and the supporting back office.
- Acquired Microsoft SQL Server Administration knowledge
- · Acquired Cisco and HP switching knowledge
- Acquired Cisco ASA and Router knowledge
- Wrote software applications in VBScript, VB.Net, Powershell, and SQL for inspection by the WSGC and deployed in the field.
- Promoted to Systems Architect in 2013
- · Acted as knowledge base for field technicians regarding any systems in Washington State.
- Provided training and documentation for field technicians.
- Maintained Change Management tickets in both JIRA and Salesforce
- Provided 24/7/365 outage support.
- · Supported Windows and Linux servers
- · Supported HP, Dell, and Toshiba systems
- Supported Hyper-V (Windows) and ESXi (VMware) virtual machine solutions.
- Supported Microsoft Windows Active Directory.

#### **Customer Service Representative**

T.S.C.Net - Silverdale, WA

Sept 1996 to June 2000

Provided Dial-up Internet support for a local Internet Service Provider.

- Provided professional telephone and in-person computer support.
- Worked with Windows and Linux Systems.
- Responsible for maintaining clients' accounts.
- Resolved customer information and complaints
- · Handled cash and credit card transactions

# **EDUCATION**

# **MCSE in Microsoft Technologies**

Paladin Data - Poulsbo, WA November 2000 to February 2001

## **Associate in Computer Science**

**Olympic College** - Bremerton, WA September 1999 to June 2000

# High school or equivalent in Computer Science

**Central Kitsap High School** - Silverdale, WA September 1997 to June 1999

## **SKILLS**

- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Microsoft Windows Server
- Cisco Switching
- Virtualization
- Active Directory
- Vmware
- System Administrator

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES**

### **MCSE**

Present

Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer